glaad.org 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy | GLAAD

## Privacy Policy

GLAAD is committed to protecting the privacy of our constituents. We have created this policy to outline the protection and use of personal information collected through our website, direct marketing, special events, or other interactions with GLAAD.

We define personal information as information that can be linked to a specific individual (e.g. name, address, phone number, e-mail address or any other information provided to us by members or website users).

## How we use the information gathered when you sign up to become a member of GLAAD or use GLAAD's on-line services

GLAAD gathers contact information when you register on glaad.org; contribute to GLAAD on-line, by mail, or on the telephone; when you participate in an event; or contact GLAAD. We use this information to send GLAAD and LGBTQ-related action alerts, event invitations, updates, press releases as well as information about GLAAD's programmatic accomplishments and initiatives, volunteer opportunities, membership and renewal appeals.

GLAAD collects information from our supporters, volunteers, and donors, including information from the internet, as well as through oral, written, or electronic communications. GLAAD ensures that information about donations will be handled with respect and confidentiality to the extent provided by law.

GLAAD collects and maintains donor information that is voluntarily provided to us, such as: 1) name, address, telephone number and e-mail address; gift giving information (including payment information); 2) information on events attended, publications received and special requests for information related to GLAAD or its programs; and 3) information provided in the form of comments and suggestions. Payment information is used only for donation or payment processing and is not retained for other purposes.  GLAAD will not sell, rent, lease or trade your information to other organizations. 

GLAAD uses this information to provide our donors, volunteers, and supporters with better service and with information about GLAAD’s events and support or volunteer opportunities. All GLAAD donors are entitled to information about the organization’s mission, the way the organization intends to use donated resources, and its capacity to use donations effectively for their intended purposes.

GLAAD complies fully with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). GLAAD does not knowingly collect identifiable personal information from children under age 13. If we discover that a person under the age of 13 has provided us with any personally identifiable information, we will delete that information from our systems. We are unable to reply to information requests from children under the age of 13, if so identified. A parent or guardian must initiate any requests for information from children under the age of 13 on their behalf. We encourage parents to supervise children when they browse the Internet.

GLAAD does not specifically ask children under 18 for any information and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information about them.

GLAAD also gathers aggregate information about website usage. Our web server automatically records the domain name and Internet Protocol (IP) address of each visitor to our site. We collect and analyze this information, which helps us determine which pages are most frequently visited, to improve the site and its resources for our visitors. GLAAD does not track individual usage of our website.

GLAAD does not share personal information with other organizations.

## How your information is protected

GLAAD holds your personal information to the highest level of confidence and security. Our website is securely protected against the loss, theft, misuse or misrepresentation of information under our control. Access to GLAAD's database information is limited only to specific qualified GLAAD employees. Additionally, when you make a contribution to GLAAD on-line, your financial information is transmitted using a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser encrypt, or scramble, data before being sent to our payment processor.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can ever be 100% secure. While we strive to protect your information to the fullest extent, we cannot ensure or completely guarantee the security of such information.

We take the utmost precaution to keep your credit card information safe and secure. But if you are uncomfortable submitting your credit card information online, contact Donor Services at 646-871-8022. 

## How to unsubscribe from mailing lists

To remove your name from our email or postal mailing list please call Donor Services at 646-871-8022 or email [donorservices@glaad.org](mailto:donorservices@glaad.org) indicating what type of communication you received from us and at what address.

## Acceptance of Constituent Privacy Policy

To further our mission and better serve our constituents, GLAAD is continually improving and adding new functionality and features to our Web site and improving and adding to its existing services and programs. Because of these ongoing changes and the changing nature of technology, GLAAD's information practices will change from time to time.

If and when its information practices change, GLAAD will post the policy changes to its Web site to notify its constituents of the changes and, where appropriate and practical, give them the opportunity to "opt-out" of the new programs and practices. If you are concerned about how your personal information is used, please check back at the GLAAD site frequently or contact Donor Services at 646-871-8022.

## How to contact GLAAD with questions, comments or concerns regarding privacy issues.

Questions, comments or concerns regarding GLAAD's privacy policy or information sent to you by GLAAD, please email [donorservices@glaad.org](mailto:donorservices@glaad.org).  You can also reach us via US Mail by sending requests to:

GLAAD Donor  Services  
104 W 29th St, 4th Floor  
New York, NY 10001

 _Last Updated November 7, 2019_
